Guide to the James Rowland Angell, President of Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, 1921-1937; Series I
  - Davis, Jerome
    - Correspondence with College and University Presidents and School Masters (Box 58, Folder 595-596)
    - Correspondence with Corporation, Alumni Board, Alumni Fund, Foundation Officers (Box 58, Folder 597-598)
    - Letters approving termination of appointment (Box 58, Folder 599)
    - Letters from the American Federation of Teachers (Box 59, Folder 600)
    - Letters from Yale Faculty re: termination of appointment (Box 59, Folder 601)
    - Letters of protest from Alumni (Box 59, Folder 602-603)
    - Letters of protest from non-Yale organizations (Box 59, Folder 604)
    - Press statements (Box 59, Folder 605-606)
    - Protests and Resolutions Teacher organizations (Box 59, Folder 607-608)
    - Protests and Resolutions Labor unions and organizations (Box 59, Folder 609)
    - Protests and Resolutions Labor unions and organizations (Box 60, Folder 610)
    - F.H. Wiggin, Reports of interviews (Box 60, Folder 611-612)
    - Yale News Release on Davis investigation, replies to release (Box 60, Folder 613)
  - Davison, Frederick Trubee (Box 60, Folder 614)
  - Davison, Henry P., Memorial scholarships (Box 60, Folder 615-616)
  - Day, Clive (Box 60, Folder 617)
  - Day, George P. (Box 60, Folder 618-621)
  - Dea-Def (Box 61, Folder 622)
  - Def-Dem (Box 61, Folder 623)
  - Deans (Box 61, Folder 624)
  - Deans, Selection of and changes in by-laws, correspondence (Box 61, Folder 625)
  - Debating Association (Box 61, Folder 626)
  - Debating Association, South American trip, 1930 (Box 61, Folder 627)
  - Degrees, Votes regarding (Box 61, Folder 628)
  - Delta Kappa Epsilon (Box 61, Folder 629)
  - Den-Dez (Box 61, Folder 630)
  - Departmental Chairmen meetings, 1925-1932 (Box 61, Folder 631)
  - Departmental Chairmen meetings, 1933-1937 (Box 61, Folder 632)
  - Departmental reports, 1930-1931, 1934-1935 (Box 61, Folder 633)
  - Departments (Box 61, Folder 634)
  - Depew, Ganson (Box 62, Folder 635)
  - Derby Regatta, 1926 (Box 62, Folder 636-637)
  - de Silva, Albert Memorial Fund (Box 62, Folder 638)
  - de Terra, Helmut (Box 62, Folder 639-641)
  - Di (Box 62, Folder 642)
  - Dining hall (Box 62, Folder 643-645)
  - Diplomatic Service (Box 62, Folder 646)
  - Disarmament Conference (Box 62, Folder 647)
  - Dissenters (Box 62, Folder 648)
  - Divinity School
    - 1922-1937 (Box 63, Folder 649-656)
    - Centennial (Box 64, Folder 657)
    - Interseminary Commission for Training the Rural Ministry (Box 64, Folder 658)
    - Minutes, 1929-1933 (Box 64, Folder 659)
    - Minutes, 1934-1937 (Box 64, Folder 660)
    - Summer courses with Union Theological Seminary (Box 64, Folder 661)
  - Divisions, Faculty of Arts and Sciences (Box 64, Folder 662)
  - Do (Box 64, Folder 663-664)
  - Dodge lectures (Box 64, Folder 665-666)
  - Dormitories (Box 64, Folder 667)
  - Dormitories, Proposed women's (Box 64, Folder 668)
  - Douglas, Beverly (Box 64, Folder 669)
  - Dramatic Art, Department of
    - 1923-1937 (Box 65, Folder 670-674)
    - Baker, George P. (Box 65, Folder 675)
    - Harkness, Edward S. (Box 65, Folder 676)
    - Meeks, Everett (Box 65, Folder 677)
    - Nicoll, Allardyce (Box 66, Folder 678)
    - Theater Building (Box 66, Folder 679)
  - Dramatic Association
    - Miscellaneous (Box 66, Folder 680)
    - Petitions re: Woolley (Abbot-Hurd) (Box 66, Folder 681)
    - Petitions re: Woolley (Hyde-Wright) (Box 66, Folder 682)
    - Woolley, Edgar M. (Box 66, Folder 683-685)
  - Du (Box 66, Folder 686-687)
  - Dudley Professorship of Railroad Engineering (Box 66, Folder 688)
  - Duggan, Stephen P. (Box 66, Folder 689)
  - Duncan, George M. (Box 67, Folder 690)
  - Dunn, Frederick Sherwood (Box 67, Folder 691)
  - Dunn, Gano (Box 67, Folder 692)
  - Dupont Fellowship in Chemistry (Box 67, Folder 693)
  - Dyer, Truman D. Memorial Fund (Box 67, Folder 694)
  - E (Box 68, Folder 695-696)
  - Eastern Association of College Deans and Advisors of Men (Box 68, Folder 697)
  - Eastern Sociological Conference (Box 68, Folder 698)
  - Economics Department (Box 68, Folder 699)
  - Economics and Public Utilities, Institute for Research in Land (Box 68, Folder 700)
  - Economics, Sociology and Government, Department of (Box 68, Folder 701-703)
    General note
    See: box 174, folder 1853-1854
  - Economics, Sociology and Government Social Science-Government and Political (Box 69, Folder 704)
  - Economics, Sociology and Government Social Science-Yale section of Industrial Relations (Box 69, Folder 705)
  - Education Department (Box 69, Folder 706-709)
  - Education, Government Office of (Box 69, Folder 710)
  - Education, School of (Box 69, Folder 711)
  - Education, Summer Conference in (Box 69, Folder 712)
  - Educational Policy Committee (Box 69, Folder 713-714)
  - Educational Policy Committee, minutes (Box 70, Folder 715-717)
  - Eg (Box 70, Folder 718)
  - Einstein, Dr. Albert (Box 70, Folder 719)
  - Eliot, Charles W., President-Emeritus 90th birthday celebration (Box 70, Folder 720)
  - Em (Box 70, Folder 721)
  - Emeritus, Committee on Title (Box 70, Folder 722)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 70, Folder 723)
  - Endowment Fund (Box 71, Folder 724-726)
  - Endowment Fund-Capital (Box 71, Folder 727-728)
  - Endowment Fund, Capital Fund Drive (Box 71, Folder 729-730)
  - Endowment Fund, Capital Fund Drive (Box 72, Folder 731-732)
  - Engagement Books, 1921-1926 (Box 72, Folder 733-735)
  - Engagement Books, 1927-1937 (Box 73, Folder 736-741)
  - Engineering at Yale (Box 74, Folder 742)
  - Engineering, Chemical (Box 74, Folder 743)
  - Engineering, Civil (Box 74, Folder 744)
  - Engineering, Divisions (Box 74, Folder 745)
  - Engineering, Drawing (Box 74, Folder 746)
  - Engineering. Economics Foundation (Box 74, Folder 747)
  - Engineering Education, Society for the Promotion of (Box 74, Folder 748)
  - Engineering, Electrical (Box 74, Folder 749)
  - Engineering Experiment Station (Box 74, Folder 750)
  - Engineering, Mechanics (Box 74, Folder 751-752)
  - Engineering, School of (Box 74, Folder 753-754)
  - Engineering, School of, Committee on Private Consulting Practice (Box 74, Folder 755)
  - Engineering, School of, minutes (Box 74, Folder 756)
  - Engineering Societies (Box 74, Folder 757)
  - English Department (Box 75, Folder 758-760)
  - English Department, Acting Chairmanship (Box 75, Folder 761)
  - English Department, Chairmen (Box 75, Folder 762)
  - English, Henry F., Bequest (Box 75, Folder 763)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 75, Folder 764)
  - Engraved forms of announcements (Box 75, Folder 765)
  - Eno, William P.-Eno Foundation (Box 75, Folder 766)
  - Entrance requirements (Box 75, Folder 767)
  - Er (Box 75, Folder 768)
  - Erickson, C. Telford (Box 75, Folder 769)
  - Exchange relations-hip with Middle Western colleges (Box 75, Folder 770)
  - Expenses (student) (Box 75, Folder 771)
  - Experimental college (Box 75, Folder 772)
  - Extension courses (Box 75, Folder 773)
  - F (Box 76, Folder 774)
  - Faculty (Box 76, Folder 775)
  - Faculty applications for positions on the Faculty in connection with graduate work (Box 76, Folder 776)
  - Faculty-Assistant Professorships (Box 76, Folder 777)
  - Faculty-Associate Professorships (Box 76, Folder 778)
  - Faculty Club (Box 76, Folder 779)
  - Faculty Club for Men (Box 76, Folder 780)
  - Faculty Entertainment Committee (Box 76, Folder 781)
  - Faculty housing (Box 76, Folder 782)
  - Faculty lists (Box 76, Folder 783)
  - Faculty members, Letters from re: salary increase (Box 76, Folder 784)
  - Faculty opinions, testimonies (Box 76, Folder 785)
  - Faculty, salaries (Box 77, Folder 786)
  - Faculty Women's Guild (Box 77, Folder 787)
  - Fairchild, Fred R. (Box 77, Folder 788)
  - Farnham, Henry W. (Box 77, Folder 789)
  - Farnum, Thomas W. (Box 77, Folder 790)
  - Farnum, W.W. property (Box 77, Folder 791)
  - Farwell, John V. (Box 77, Folder 792)
  - Fatio, Monsieur (Box 77, Folder 793)
  - Fe (Box 77, Folder 794)
  - Fi (Box 78, Folder 795-796)
  - Finance committees (Box 78, Folder 797-800)
  - Finance committees, Fisher, H.B. (Box 78, Folder 801)
  - Finance committees, Fisher, Irving (Box 79, Folder 802)
  - Finance committees, Fisher, Samuel H. (Box 79, Folder 803-804)
  - Financial Aid
    See: box 15, folders 170-172
  - Financial Campaign
    - Alumni reaction to proposal (Box 80, Folder 805)
    - Bannard, Otto T., open letter to from President Angell (Box 80, Folder 806)
    - Books, pamphlets, progress reports (Box 80, Folder 807-810)
    - Books, pamphlets, progress reports (Box 81, Folder 811-812)
    - Brown, John Crosby (Box 81, Folder 813)
    - Brown, John Crosby and Freeberg, Victor O. (Box 81, Folder 814)
    - Chairman-Committees (Box 81, Folder 815)
    - Day, George Parmly (Box 81, Folder 816)
    - Endowment Drives elsewhere (Box 82, Folder 817-818)
    - Faculty comments (Box 82, Folder 819)
    - Form letters to committeemen (Box 82, Folder 820)
    - New York Conference, Regarding launching of (Box 82, Folder 821)
    - New York Dinner, 1926 February 20 (Box 82, Folder 822)
    - Other university officers and graduates (Box 82, Folder 823)
    - Other university officers and graduates (Box 83, Folder 824-825)
    - President's statement (Box 83, Folder 826)
    - Shimp, B.W. (Box 83, Folder 827-829)
    - Student meetings (Box 83, Folder 830)
  - Fl (Box 84, Folder 831-833)
  - Fleischmann Fellowships (Box 84, Folder 834)
  - Flexner, Abraham (Box 84, Folder 835)
  - Foch Convocation (Box 84, Folder 836)
  - Foreign Learned Societies and International Congress meetings (Box 84, Folder 837)
  - Foreign Relations group (Box 84, Folder 838)
  - Foreign students (Box 84, Folder 839)
  - Forester, Max (Box 84, Folder 840)
  - Forestry School (Box 84, Folder 841)
  - Forestry School (Box 85, Folder 842-843)
  - Forestry School, Forest Experiment Station (Box 85, Folder 844)
  - Forestry School, minutes (Box 85, Folder 845)
  - Fort Hale Park and Lighthouse Point (Box 85, Folder 846)
  - Fr (Box 85, Folder 847)
  - Frasch, Herman Foundation for Chemical Research (Box 85, Folder 848)
  - Frauds (Box 85, Folder 849)
  - French Department (Box 85, Folder 850)
  - French Exchange Professorship (Box 85, Folder 851)
  - French Government Yale Fund (Box 85, Folder 852)
  - French oratorical contest, Comit France-Amerique (Box 85, Folder 853)
  - French phonetics laboratory (Box 85, Folder 854)
  - French, Robert Dudley (Box 85, Folder 855)
  - Freshman, Associate Dean of, Edward S. Noyes (Box 86, Folder 856)
  - Freshman Deanship (Box 86, Folder 857)
  - Freshman disturbance, Class of 1926, 1923 June 4 (Box 86, Folder 858)
  - Freshman dormitories (Box 86, Folder 859)
  - Freshman housing (Box 86, Folder 860)
  - Freshman lecture, 1922 February (Box 86, Folder 861)
  - Freshman Scholarship Test Program, Noyes-Crawford (Box 86, Folder 862)
  - Freshman segregation (Box 86, Folder 863)
  - Freshman year
    - 1921-1937 (Box 86, Folder 864-868)
    - Minutes (Box 86, Folder 869)
  - Fri (Box 87, Folder 870)
  - Friends of Medical Progress, Society of (Box 87, Folder 871)
  - Frish, Ragnar (Box 87, Folder 872)
  - Furniss, Provost Edgar S. (Box 87, Folder 873)
  - Ga (Box 88, Folder 874-877)
  - Galt, John R. (Box 88, Folder 878)
  - Garland, Annie G.K., Scholarship Fund (Box 88, Folder 879)
  - Garvan, Francis P. (Box 88, Folder 880-881)
  - Garvan, Mabel Brady (Box 88, Folder 880-881)
  - Garvan, Francis P., Whitney Collections of Sporting Art (Box 88, Folder 882)
  - Garvan, Mabel Brady Collection (Box 88, Folder 883)
  - Garvan, Mabel Brady Collection of American Gold Coins (Box 88, Folder 884)
  - Gay, Edwin F. (Box 88, Folder 885)
  - Ge (Box 89, Folder 886)
  - General Education Board (Box 89, Folder 887-888)
  - General Education Board, International Education Board (Box 89, Folder 889)
  - General Education Board, International Education Board, Nominating Committee (Box 89, Folder 890-894)
  - General Education Board, Survey Committee (Box 89, Folder 895)
  - Genetics, Sixth International Conference (Box 89, Folder 896)
  - Geography (Box 89, Folder 897)
  - Geology Department (Box 89, Folder 898-899)
  - Geology Department, Chairmanship (Box 89, Folder 900)
  - German-Amerika Institut, Invitation, 1934 (Box 90, Folder 901)
  - German Department (Box 90, Folder 902-904)
  - German scholars, Displaced, including Committee of the Institute of International Education (Box 90, Folder 905-907)
  - German scholarship, Institute of International Education, Hochschild, Berthold Marks, Marcus M. (Box 90, Folder 908)
  - Gettysburg College (Box 90, Folder 909)
  - Gherini, Ambrose, Prize (Box 90, Folder 910)
  - Gi (Box 90, Folder 911-912)
  - Gibbs, Josiah Willard Memorial (Box 91, Folder 913)
  - Glee Club (Box 91, Folder 914)
  - Go (Box 91, Folder 915-917)
  - Gotze, Albrecht, Semitics (Box 91, Folder 918)
  - Goodrich, James Raymond Memorial Fund (Box 91, Folder 919)
  - Government, Federal Emergency Adult Education Project (Box 91, Folder 920)
  - Government and International Relations Department (Box 91, Folder 921)
  - Government officers, Yale men (Box 91, Folder 922)
  - Government Service, University Assistance in C.W.A. Projects, etc. (Box 91, Folder 923)
  - Gr (Box 91, Folder 924)
  - Graduates Club (Box 91, Folder 925)
  - Graduate degrees (Box 92, Folder 926)
  - Graduate School (Box 92, Folder 927-930)
  - Graduate School
    - Archeological Committee, minutes (Box 92, Folder 931)
    - Associate Deanship (Box 92, Folder 932)
    - Deanship (Box 92, Folder 933)
    - Departments of Study (Box 92, Folder 934-935)
    - Fine Arts, Program of Development (Box 92, Folder 936)
    - Furniss, Edgar S., Dean (Box 92, Folder 937)
    - Humanities Program American School of Ideological Studies (Box 92, Folder 938)
    - Humanities Program Babylonian Collection (Box 92, Folder 939)
    - Humanities Program Dura, General (Box 92, Folder 940-941)
    - Humanities Program Dura, General (Box 93, Folder 942-943)
    - Humanities Program Dura, Hopkins, Clark (Box 93, Folder 944-945)
    - Humanities Program Dura, Papyri (Box 93, Folder 946-947)
    - Humanities Program Dura, Fillet, Maurice (Box 93, Folder 948-952)
    - Humanities Program Dura, Rostovtzeff, Michael (Box 94, Folder 953-955)
    - Humanities Program General Education Board (Box 94, Folder 956-960)
    - Humanities Program Jerash, General (Box 94, Folder 961-963)
    - Humanities Program Jerash, General (Box 95, Folder 964-970)
    - Humanities Program Linguistic Survey (Box 95, Folder 971)
    - Minutes (Box 95, Folder 972-973)
    - New York State Fellowship in Public Finance (Box 95, Folder 974)
    - Research Fund in Language and Literature (Box 95, Folder 975)
    - Research Fund in Humanistic Studies (Box 95, Folder 975)
    - Scholarships and fellowships (Box 96, Folder 976-977)
  - Graves, Henry S. (Box 96, Folder 978)
  - Gre (Box 96, Folder 979-980)
  - Greene, Edward B. (Box 96, Folder 981-982)
  - Gri-Gro (Box 96, Folder 983)
  - Grp-Gz (Box 96, Folder 984)
  - Gundelfinger, George Frederick (Box 96, Folder 985)
  - H (Box 97, Folder 986-987)
  - Hadden (Briton) Memorial (Box 97, Folder 988)
  - Hadley (Arthur T.) Fund (Box 97, Folder 989)
  - Hadley-Taft Memorials (Box 97, Folder 990)
  - Hale (Nathan) receipt books, correspondence (Box 97, Folder 991)
  - Ham (Box 97, Folder 992-993)
  - Hamilton-Hader Fellowship Fund (Box 97, Folder 994)
  - Har (Box 98, Folder 995)
  - Harding, Warren G. (Box 98, Folder 996)
  - Harkness, Edward S. (Box 98, Folder 997)
  - Harkness, Mary Stillman (Box 98, Folder 997)
  - Harkness, Stephen V., Mrs. (Box 98, Folder 998)
  - Harkness etchings (Box 98, Folder 999)
  - Harkness Memorial Quadrangle (Box 98, Folder 1000)
  - Harkness portrait, Warden, William G. (Box 98, Folder 1001)
  - Hartwell, John A., Dr. (Box 98, Folder 1002)
  - Harvard Tercentenary (Box 98, Folder 1003)
  - Harvard University (Box 98, Folder 1004-1005)
  - Has (Box 99, Folder 1006)
  - Haskins and Sells (Box 99, Folder 1007-1008)
  - Haverford College (Box 99, Folder 1009)
  - Hawley, Mary E. (Box 99, Folder 1010)
  - He (Box 99, Folder 1011)
  - Headmasters' Association (Box 99, Folder 1012)
  - Health, Poliomyelitis (Box 99, Folder 1013)
  - Health Department (Box 100, Folder 1014)
  - Health Department, new buildings (Box 100, Folder 1015)
  - Healy-Ives Fund (Box 100, Folder 1016)
  - Heidelberg University, celebration (Box 100, Folder 1017-1018)
  - Heinz, Howard (Box 100, Folder 1019)
  - Hel (Box 100, Folder 1020)
  - Hemingway, Samuel B. (Box 100, Folder 1021)
  - Henderson and Davie, Income and living costs of a university faculty (Box 100, Folder 1022)
  - Henderson, Yandell (Box 101, Folder 1023-1025)
  - Henry, Lady Fund (Box 101, Folder 1026)
  - Hep-Her (Box 101, Folder 1027)
  - Herr, Edwin W. (Box 101, Folder 1028)
  - Hi (Box 101, Folder 1029)
  - Hibben, John Grier (Box 101, Folder 1030)
  - Hillhouse, James T. (Box 102, Folder 1031)
  - Hill School, The (Box 102, Folder 1032)
  - Hillyer, Drayton, Mrs., Bequest (Box 102, Folder 1033)
  - History Department (Box 102, Folder 1034-1037)
  - History Department, The Arts and Letters (Box 102, Folder 1038)
  - Ho (Box 102, Folder 1039)
  - Hol (Box 102, Folder 1040-1041)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1913, 1921-1935 (Box 103, Folder 1042-1050)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1935-1937 (Box 104, Folder 1051)
    - Army and Navy Officers (Box 104, Folder 1052)
    - unfiled material, 1936-1937 (Box 104, Folder 1053)
  - Honors courses (Box 104, Folder 1054)
  - Hooker, Richard (Box 104, Folder 1055)
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 104, Folder 1056)
  - Hoover, John Edgar
    See: box 182, folder 1962-1969
  - Hopkins, Johns University (Box 104, Folder 1057-1058)
  - Hor (Box 104, Folder 1059-1060)
  - Howe, Ernest Memorial Fund (Box 104, Folder 1061)
  - Howland, Charles P. (Box 105, Folder 1062)
  - Howland, Charles P. Memorial Fund (Box 105, Folder 1063)
  - Howland, Frances L. Fund for Political Science (Box 105, Folder 1064)
  - Howland Memorial at Yale (Box 105, Folder 1065)
  - Howland Prize (Box 105, Folder 1066-1069)
  - Howland Prize, Baker, Professor Philip J. (Dodge Lectures) (Box 105, Folder 1070)
  - Howland Prize, de Madariaga, Don Salvador (Box 105, Folder 1071)
  - Howland Prize, Ostberg, Ragnar (Box 105, Folder 1072)
  - Hu (Box 106, Folder 1073)
  - Humphrey, May Fund (Box 106, Folder 1074)
  - Hun (Box 106, Folder 1075-1076)
  - Huntington, Ellsworth (Box 106, Folder 1077)
  - Huntington Property (Box 106, Folder 1078)
  - Hutchins, Robert M. (Box 106, Folder 1079)
  - I (Box 107, Folder 1080-1086)
  - Illinois, University of (Box 107, Folder 1087)
  - Inauguration of Angell, Register
    see: box 203, folio
  - Industrial Administration (Box 107, Folder 1088)
  - Infirmary (Box 107, Folder 1089)
  - Institute for Advanced Study (Box 107, Folder 1090)
  - Institute of Human Relations
    - Adolescent Children Studies (Box 108, Folder 1091)
    - Applications for positions (Box 108, Folder 1092)
    - Assignment of space in new building (Box 108, Folder 1093)
    - Budgets (Box 108, Folder 1094)
    - Building, General Education Board, Rockefeller Fund Gifts (Box 108, Folder 1095)
    - Bulletin, 1931 (Box 108, Folder 1096)
    - Bureau of Human Standards (Box 108, Folder 1097)
    - Bureau of Human Standards Draper, Wickliffe P. (Box 108, Folder 1098)
    - Carnegie Corporation (Box 108, Folder 1099)
    - Change in administrative organization (Box 108, Folder 1100)
    - Committee to secure funds for Medical Center (Box 108, Folder 1101)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 108, Folder 1102)
    - Dedication of Building (Box 108, Folder 1103)
    - d'Herelle, Felix, Dr. (Box 108, Folder 1104)
    - Dodge, Raymond (Box 108, Folder 1105)
    - Dusser de Barenne, J.G., Dr. (Box 108, Folder 1106)
    - Education Board, General gift for Psychiatry (RF29002) (Box 109, Folder 1107)
    - Eugenics-Curtis (Box 109, Folder 1108)
    - Executive Committee (Box 109, Folder 1109)
    - Executive Committee, minutes (Box 109, Folder 1110)
    - Executive Committee: Reorganization of administrative set-up, Committee on Institute of Human Relations (Box 109, Folder 1111)
    - Fitkin Gift, Raleigh Fitkin Memorial (Box 109, Folder 1112)
    - Flexner-Winternitz correspondence (Box 109, Folder 1113)
    - General (Box 109, Folder 1114-1115)
    - Healy-Bronner appointments and project (Box 109, Folder 1116)
    - Hilton, Maurice H. (Box 109, Folder 1117)
    - Hull, Clark L., appointment (Box 109, Folder 1118)
    - Human Welfare Group, appeals for gifts (Box 110, Folder 1119-1120)
    - Human Welfare Group, Dinner, New York, 1930 February 17 (Box 110, Folder 1121)
    - Human Welfare Group, Dinners and letters of comment (Box 110, Folder 1122)
    - Human Welfare Group, English (Alice Kimball) Fund (Box 110, Folder 1123)
    - Human Welfare Group, Health Service Plan (Box 110, Folder 1124)
    - Human Welfare Group, National Advisory Committee (Box 110, Folder 1125-1126)
    - Human Welfare Group, publications (Box 110, Folder 1127)
    - Institute of Human Behavior (Box 111, Folder 1128-1129)
    - Institute of Psychology (Box 111, Folder 1130-1132)
    - Institute of Psychology, plans for inaugurating work, staff gifts (Box 111, Folder 1133-1134)
    - Kaempffert, Waldemar (Box 111, Folder 1135)
    - Kahn, Eugen (Box 111, Folder 1136)
    - Letters received regarding (Box 112, Folder 1137)
    - Lund, Harold H. (Box 112, Folder 1138)
    - Macy Foundation; Shenton, Herbert N., proposed program for research on the Philosophy of Science (Box 112, Folder 1139)
    - May, Mark A. (Box 112, Folder 1140)
    - Medical School development (Box 112, Folder 1141)
    - Medical School, Fluid Research Fund Rockefeller Fund (Box 112, Folder 1142)
    - Medical School, unfiled material (Box 112, Folder 1143-1145)
    - Motor vehicle accidents (Box 112, Folder 1146)
    - Oral Pathology Library Medical School, Carnegie Corporation gift (Box 112, Folder 1147)
    - Osborn, Frederick (Box 112, Folder 1148)
    - Parker, Judge, endowment (Box 113, Folder 1149)
    - Physiatric laboratory, appointment of W.R. and C.C. Miles (Box 113, Folder 1150)
    - Preliminary conferences with foundation representatives (Box 113, Folder 1151)
    - Projects (Box 113, Folder 1152)
    - Projects, budgets, Slesinger, Donald (Box 113, Folder 1153)
    - Provisional staff and appointments (Box 113, Folder 1154)
    - Psychiatric and mental hygiene budgets (Box 113, Folder 1155)
    - Racca, Vittorio (Box 113, Folder 1156)
    - Research and advanced study in adult education (Box 113, Folder 1157)
    - Roberts, Helen H. (Box 113, Folder 1158)
    - Robinson, Mr. and Mrs. Edward (Box 113, Folder 1159)
    - Rockefeller Foundation and Carnegie Corporation, gift for dental pathology (Box 114, Folder 1160)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, psychological child development, social science research (Box 114, Folder 1161)
    - Sapir, Edward, Sterling Professor of Anthropology, Peabody Museum (Box 114, Folder 1162)
    - Shimp, Byron W. (Box 114, Folder 1163)
    - Shop of Institute (Box 114, Folder 1164)
    - Slesinger, Donald (Box 114, Folder 1165)
    - Special Committee of Interests of Work in Psychology (Box 114, Folder 1166)
    - Statistical laboratory (Box 114, Folder 1167)
    - Thomas, Dorothy (Box 114, Folder 1168)
    - Vincent, George E. (Box 114, Folder 1169)
    - Wissler, Clark (Box 114, Folder 1170)
    - Yale Graduate Placement Bureau, Aid through Department of Personnel Study (Box 114, Folder 1171)
    - Yale University Press, arrangements re: publications (Box 114, Folder 1172)
  - Institute of International Education (Box 115, Folder 1173-1175)
  - Insurance, Group (Box 115, Folder 1176)
  - Insurance, Life (Box 115, Folder 1177)
  - Interdepartmental charges (Box 115, Folder 1178)